DANILO VILHENA

danilo.vilhena@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/danilo-vilhena/en https://github.com/danilovilhena https://danilovilhena.com/

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Working with web development for a year, I focus on the front-end and the design part of applications I develop. Always concerned with accessibility, providing a good user experience and maintaining a clean and organized code base.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-time Front-end Developer

At <u>LEAD Dell</u> August 2021 - Present

Intern Front-end Developer

At LEAD Dell

August 2020 - August 2021

LEAD is a center of research and development that transforms the life of thousands of people through technology, research and innovation.

- I've worked with the product owner and the team of developers to build accessible websites and desktop applications in Vue.js, Angular and Electron.
- I've helped develop a browser extension that makes the web more usable and accessible for people with visual impairments, preventing such users from being excluded from access.
- Refactored and organized older code bases in order to increase performance and improve the experience of other developers with this source code.
- Worked with Agile methodologies in the projects I participated in. Specifically, Scrum with sprints, daily meetings and sprint reviews; and Kanban boards to divide the work into columns and visualize all tasks of the sprint.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's in Computer Science (In progress)

<u>UNIFOR (University of Fortaleza)</u> August 2019 - July 2023

OTHER PROJECTS

Front-end Developer + Designer

Give me a font March 2021

Developed a website to give the user a random free font from Google Fonts based on their choice of font style, such as sans-serif, serif or monospace. Used Gatsby to generate static pages and Tailwind for faster

and more organized styling. Also I optimized the application using PageSpeed Insights for performance and made adjustments for SEO purposes.

Instagram Content Creator

Instagram Account

January 2021 - May 2021

Started to create Instagram posts on alternate days about topics of general programming and web development so that I could maintain a constant study habit of new things and also help other developers learn with me.

Front-end Developer

Personal Portfolio

January 2021

Developed a website to showcase my personal portfolio using Gatsby to improve the performance by generating static pages. Internationalized the page to English and Portuguese and made adjustments according to PageSpeed Insights for performance and Google Search Console for SEO purposes.

Fullstack Web Developer

Blog

November 2020 - December 2020

As a project for a college subject, I developed a blog organized by topics and with user authentication. I designed the project in Figma and used Angular + Bootstrap for the front-end, Express for the back-end and MongoDB for the database.

Front-end Developer + Web Scraping

COVID-19 Dashboard

November 2020 - December 2020

As a project for a college subject, I designed and developed a dashboard that consumes a couple of APIs to get COVID data both in Brazil and in the world. After consuming the data, I format and treat it to avoid possible API's failures. The web scraping was necessary to find out the amount of money sent to each brazilian state, because there weren't any APIs available with that information. The design was made in Figma, the front-end was built in Angular and web scraping in Python.

Front-end Developer

Mail capture page

Landing page

October 2020 - November 2020

For a client of mine, I designed and developed a page to capture possible customers emails for a marketing strategy and another page to present a product to these customers and give them the option to buy it. Used Gatsby for performance purposes, Tailwind for a faster CSS developing experience and Mailchimp for the email marketing.